There are secret parking spots in space
and one of them is really special. These
are five locations where the
gravitational pole from the sun and the
earth perfectly matches the force needed
to move with them. Which means that
objects placed in any [music] of these
spots tend to stay put. But some of them
have some problems. If you stop here,
you're in Earth's orbit, but the sun is
constantly between you and Earth, which
is blocking any communication. So that
sucks. These two are cool, but pretty
far away from Earth. So again, not great
for sending data home. This spot is
actually pretty great. If you stop here,
Earth's gravity counteracts the sun just
enough so that you rotate in sync with
the Earth. So, you can get a great view
of the sun, which is perfect for solar
telescopes. And if you turn around, you
get a constant view of Earth during the
daytime, which is perfect for monitoring
Earth, but it's blocking something else,
which is why this parking spot is
special. The combined pull from the Sun
and the Earth keeps you in pace with
Earth's orbit. You're close, so
communicating is easy. And while you
don't get a great view of Earth because
it's always dark, if you turn around,
you'll get the best view of the rest of
the universe. Which is why we sent so
many telescopes here. And we just sent a
new one. So to see that subscribe.